On a summer weekend in 1963, four girlfriends made
memories that would last a lifetime.
Shag is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Zelda Barron.
Summer of 1963.
Carson is getting married to her boyfriend so her friends Melaina, Pudge and
Luanne take her to Myrtle Beach for one last irresponsible weekend.
Carson McBride, played by Phoebe Cates.
Chip, played by Scott Coffey.
Melaina Buller, played by Bridget Fonda.
Caroline "Pudge" Carmichael, played by Annabeth Gish.
Luanne Clatterbuck, played by Page Hannah.
Buzz Ravenel, played by Robert Rusler.
Shag (also known as Shag: The Movie) is a 1988 teen romantic comedy film directed by Zelda Barron and starring Phoebe
Cates, Scott Coffey, Bridget Fonda, Annabeth Gish, Page Hannah, Robert Rusler, and Tyrone Power Jr.
Set in 1963, the film follows four teenage girls who spend their last weekend together
in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina, before one of the girls gets married.
The film features Carolina shag dancing and was produced in
cooperation with the South Carolina Film Commission.
An international co-production between the United States and the United Kingdom, Shag was released in the UK on
August 12, 1988, by Palace Pictures and in the US on July 21, 1989, by Hemdale Film Corporation.
The film explores themes of dance, beach, summer, boyfriend, woman director.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.